<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activities on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</title>
    <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activities on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 percent can shape the world</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/5-percet-shapes-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/5-percet-shapes-the-world/</guid>
      <description>This activity shows that social change doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be directed by masses or majority, but few goal oriented individuals can shape the stream of river of human aimlessness. Students get an instruction to walk freely and follow others, with a small percentage of them getting clear instructions of what to do - walk towards a basketball court, walk towards a door.
Goal Students learn that if everybody is somewhat aimless and without a particular agenda, few individuals can actually instruct majority in accepting their views, if that is done subversly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baddeley Memory</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/baddeley-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/baddeley-memory/</guid>
      <description>Overview placeholder
Goal Studnets read the update of Alan Baddeley on his theory of working memory from 2004. This article is generally amazing, because it contents potentially all answers to any IB memory related question.
Structure Students read the article at home and answer these questions:
 What was the original model proposed in 1974? What is central executive? How does it differ from Atkinson and Shiffrin model? What are some of the proofs that phonological loop exists as a theoretical concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain Techniques</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/brain-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/brain-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Attachments   EEG.docx  (1339 ko)   MRI.docx  (1289 ko)   PET.docx  (432 ko)   comparing-table.docx  (10 ko)   post-mortem.docx  (673 ko)   techniques-description.docx  (33 ko)    Each table covers one method for investigating the brain. You need to:
 Understand what the method involves Interpret data from the method to understand how it works and what it tells us Identify methodological and ethical issues with using it  Comparing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Presentations</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/cognitive-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/cognitive-presentations/</guid>
      <description>List of presentations and sources for students to work on for the cognitive topic
   Title Sources     False memories Loftus, E. F., &amp;amp; Pickrell, J. E. (1995). The formation of false memories. Psychiatric Annals, 25(12), 720–725. https://blogs.brown.edu/recoveredmemory/files/2015/05/Loftus_Pickrell_PA_95.pdf   Eyewitness memory Loftus, E. F., &amp;amp; Palmer, J. C. (1974). Reconstruction of automobile destruction: An example of the interaction between language and memory. Journal of verbal learning and verbal behavior, 13(5), 585-589.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Theories in Classroom</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/cognitive-theories-in-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/cognitive-theories-in-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Overview placeholder
Goal Structure Discussion With the use of the article in attachments, try and answer the questions below:
 What are some fundamentals elements of Piaget and Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s theories? What is the process of equilibrium and how it relates to teaching? What is internalisation? Why do kids speak to themselves? Why is language important? What are major differences between tehir theories? How can we use Piatget theory in a class?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating research</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/evaluating-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/evaluating-research/</guid>
      <description>This activity focuses on students ability to read and understand even complex articles. It&amp;rsquo;s goal isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily for the student to understand everything in the text, but to be able to pinpoint important parts and to discuss valid points the article makes.
The activity follows classes on research. Students are given each question immediately after appropriate lesson has been covered (e.g. question 10 after ethics have been gone through). In the end, students hand out a summary of a scientific paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Dating</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/evolutionary-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/evolutionary-dating/</guid>
      <description> Goal Structure Ask groups of students to investigate online dating.
Schedule  Form groups of students. Ask each group to search for dating ads, preferably without pictures Define clear goal: short hookups vs long term relationships? Define good sampling - better to have data from multiple websites. Each member searches for about 10 ads. Do content analysis on those ads. Try to put results into some presentation/poster form.  Discussion Followup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forer effect, aka. blind reading</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/forer-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/forer-effect/</guid>
      <description>This activity is a good introduction to a scientific inquiry as well as discussion in the psychology vs parapsychology introduction. The Forer effect refers to the tendency of people to rate sets of statements as highly accurate for them personally even though the statements could apply to many people.
Goal Show students the importance of specific vs vague statements, demonstrate why horoscopes and psychics work and why people tend to believe in these seemingly random encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genes or Environment</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/genes-or-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/genes-or-environment/</guid>
      <description> Overview placeholder
Goal Structure Schedule Discussion Followup </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How news and research reporting differs</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/news-reporting-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/news-reporting-development/</guid>
      <description> Goal Structure Students are asked to read the NBC news report
Discussion  Are news themselves to blame? What are scientists doing to promote this? What are ethical considerations that should have been taken care of? Cna you think of other misinterpretation of research?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRB Review</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/irb-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/irb-review/</guid>
      <description> Students are given a filled in IRB which they go over thoroughly and then they are given a bad IRB and asked to &amp;ldquo;fix it&amp;rdquo;.
Goal Structure Schedule Discussion Followup   Attachments   ethics-mock-IRB-bad.pdf  (121 ko)   ethics-mock-IRB-empty.pdf  (143 ko)   ethics-mock-IRB-good.pdf  (166 ko)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie nights</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/movie-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/movie-nights/</guid>
      <description> Goal This is to
Biology  Awakenings Lucy Moon Johny Mnemonic?  Cognitive  Memento Eternal Sunshine total Recall  Social  Fight Club  Abnormal  Fight club  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observation of TV</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/observing-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/observing-tv/</guid>
      <description>Select a TV show to watch about 15 minutes of. It should be something fairly interesting, even funny. Ask students, what might be some interesting topics to investigate and to look for and then run a structured/natural observation.
Goal Practicing observation
Structure Have</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological mythbusters</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/debunking-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/debunking-myths/</guid>
      <description>Goal Present story well, learn to cite well, debunk some psychological myths.
Myth selection  We learn more effectively when taught via our preferred “learning style” Violent offenders usually have a diagnosis of mental illness Smiling makes you happy Playing Mozart&amp;rsquo;s music to Infants Boosts their Intelligence Subliminal messaging can persuade you to buy things Intelligence tests are biased towards some groups The Polygraph accurately measures dishonesty 90 percent of communication is non verbal People only use 10% of their brain power Some people are left-brained, some are right brained Human memory works like a camera, capturing accurately events we experience People can learn information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Smarties</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/sampling-smarties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/sampling-smarties/</guid>
      <description>Students buy smarties boxes and then count how many of each colour is in each box. Then we do statistical tests to determine some level of
Goal This activity trains students in sampling and statistics. Students should understand how to select an appropriate sample and how to conduct statistical analysis in excel or in other statistical software.
Structure Explain the goal of the research: To assess if the smarties come in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling poker chips</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/sampling-poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/sampling-poker/</guid>
      <description>Goal This activity shows the importance of sampling methods and how sample is just a subselect of a population and how different methods might affect the results in unpredictable or predictable (biased way).
Structure You will need either a bunch of poker chips of varied denominations or some marbles, papers with printed numbers etc. You also need sachets, bags or cups which will serve as a draw bags for the chips for the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science or pseudoscience</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/science-pseudoscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/science-pseudoscience/</guid>
      <description>This activity let&amp;rsquo;s students to pick a pseudoscientific or &amp;ldquo;junk&amp;rdquo; science topic, present to the class what it is and why it is junk science.
Goal Distinguish between real sciences and pseudo sciences. Be clear that &amp;ldquo;unreal&amp;rdquo; things are not necessarily not scientific - what makes atoms more believable than ghosts to a general public without an electron microscope? Neither can be touched, neither can be seen.
List of topics  Animal magnetism Graphology Fortune telling Rorschach test Neurolinguistic programming MBTI test Ouija board Telepathy Faith healing Telekinesis  Čištění 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Situation</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/strange-situation-scoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/strange-situation-scoring/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T Test Tongue Twisters</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/t-test-tongue-twisters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/t-test-tongue-twisters/</guid>
      <description>Students read tongue twisters in pairs and then we test who is better in the pair using parametric and non parametric t-test.
Goal The goal is to see randomness in repeating the task even in one setting. To learn t-test in excel, R or python. Studnets also learn the limitatios of some tests - having test with 3 right answers will not give enough variation ot assess what you want to assess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering fake artist</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/fake-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/fake-artist/</guid>
      <description>Synesthesia is not an unknown or entirely uncommon thing, but still. If an artist claims she sells paintings of what she hears, you&amp;rsquo;d better be certain before you buy it and start boasting to your friends.
Goal Design an experiment to prove synesthesia in an artist who claims so. Try approach it from different levels of anlaysis - bio vs cognitive. Practicing good hypothesis formulation. How to create hypothesis from theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is psychology</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/what-is-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/what-is-psychology/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is science?</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/what-is-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/what-is-science/</guid>
      <description>   Attachments   Can Science Answer This Question.pdf  (44 ko)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zodiac signs and personality</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/zodiac-personality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/activities/zodiac-personality/</guid>
      <description>Personality profiles derived from star placements during the time of one&amp;rsquo;s birth are a thorn in a foot of many psychologists. But is there a reason?
One of the old principles say, that if a theory survives for a long time, there must be some validity in it. So how is it with zodiac signs?
This activity can be preceded by the Forer effect activity
 Goal Investigate validity of zodiac personality profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>