<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internal assessment on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</title>
    <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internal assessment on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical guidelines</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/ethics/</guid>
      <description>The experiment for the internal assessment must adhere to the ethical guidelines outlined below.
 Any experimental study that creates anxiety, stress, pain or discomfort for participants is not permitted. Experiments involving deception, conformity, obedience, or any other form of harm are not permitted. The experiment must be appropriate to the sensitivities of the particular school, community and country. Any experimental study that involves unjustified deception, involuntary participation or invasion of privacy, including the inappropriate use of information and communication technology (ICT), email and the internet, must be avoided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal assessment marking</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/marking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/marking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction (6 marks)    Marks Level descriptor     0 Does not reach the standard described by the descriptors below.   1–2 The aim of the investigation is stated but its relevance is not identified. The theory or model upon which the student’s investigation is based is identified but the description is incomplete or contains errors. Null and/or research hypotheses are stated, but do not correctly identify the Independent or Dependent Variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal assessment marking checklist</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/internal-assessment/checklist/</guid>
      <description>Checklist for IA report
You cannot submit your IA report if:
 Your word count is not between 1800-2200 words You didn&amp;rsquo;t reference every idea that is not your own (-&amp;gt; 0 points for the whole IA) Your investigation is not done in experimental method with one independent variable that you were manipulating The theory/model that you based your investigation didn&amp;rsquo;t appear in peer-reviewed publication You didn&amp;rsquo;t use consistently one referencing format (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>