<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IB requirements on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</title>
    <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IB requirements on Documentation for Hugo Learn Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper 1 and 2</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/paper-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/paper-1-2/</guid>
      <description>Paper 1 Paper 1, 2 hours, Total of 49 marks
 Section A: Three short-answer questions on the core approaches to psychology (27 marks) Section B: One essay from a choice of three on the biological, cognitive and sociocultural approaches to behaviour (22 marks)  Paper 1 Marking Short answer question Paper 1 section A consists of three short-answer questions using AO1 and AO2 command terms. All three questions are compulsory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper 3</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/paper-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/paper-3/</guid>
      <description>Paper 3 Paper 3 assesses the approaches to research in psychology. The paper consists of a research scenario followed by a three short answer questions for a total of 24 marks.
Content Question 1 Question 1 will consist of all of the following questions, for a total of 9 marks. The questions will be assessed using an analytical markscheme.
 Identify the method used and outline two characteristics of the method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command terms for psychology</title>
      <link>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/command-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hejtmy.github.io/ib-psych/ib-requirements/command-terms/</guid>
      <description>Students should be familiar with the following key terms and phrases used in examination questions, which are to be understood as described below. Although these terms will be used frequently in examination questions, other terms may be used to direct students to present an argument in a specific way. The command terms used in psychology are arranged into four groups labelled assessment objectives (AO). The first three, AO1, AO2 and AO3, are hierarchical with more challenging verbs for assessment as you progress from AO1 to AO3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>